Name: Mikael Cuinet

Address: Rupert-Mayer-Strasse, 21

81379 München

Germany

Telephone: +49 (0) 176 7064 7978 Email: Mikael.Cuinet@Gmail.com

Marital status: Single

Sex: Male

Nationality: French

Age: 39

GitHub: https://github.com/MikCui

COVER LETTER:

Hello Strikerz Inc.,

With great interest have I read your Render Technical Lead job offer. I am convinced that I am the ideal candidate for you.

I am Mikael Cuinet 39, working for BMW since 13 years as a senior 3D C++ prototype developer. My team is tasked with rapid implementation in order to quickly test the design or any new technology in action on the 3 displays.

My specialty is C++, OpenGL/OpenGL ES and GLSL, though I did my master in Direct3D.

We started 3 programmers and 2 designers, I gently became the lead programmer, due to my technical skills but also my personality. Always willing to help, pedagogue, smooth and the most important a team player.

A part of my job is doing the bridge between the creatives and the serie developers. The first ones come with amazing ideas, I implement them in the prototyping car for the decision makers to decide. I then evaluate with the serie team what is doable, regarding the hardware, the performances and most important their programming constraint (same OS as Airbus, eg. no dynamic allocations). It taught me a lot about safe code practices. But I am so glad I can use the 2 + in C++ and let my creativity go for my projects.

They often invite me to their code reviews or to mentor a new programmer on the 3D topic. I also write documentations or do presentations for them since I am already working on the new Software/Hardware since few months. I had the chance to collaborate with Nvidia and work with a RTX prototype few years before it came out.

I also work with some other teams:

LIDAR, everything about environmental detection.

The navigator team. I had to reconstruct in 3D some gigantic road-crossing on 4 levels, with just a tremendous and confusing amount of data they are sending.

Some of those teams work in German, some in English, I am french. With most of them we use Agile, SCRUM, some prefer V, they know what is best for their team. I can adapt to my auditors or their methods, you do not do the same presentation if you are facing 20 programmers, 3 project managers or your 10 years nephew.

Before that I did work 2 years for the LQA at Koch Media, I started lead tester and became lead tester coordinator the next year. The game I worked on and I am the most proud of is STALKER: Clear Sky. I just love it

Working for BMW has been a great position and I am now in a role with central responsibility, however I am looking for a new challenge and I would like to work again for the video game industry. I am also looking for a remote job in order to go back to France near my family.

Strikerz Inc. seems to be a great company to work for, a game with potential (and a place to take on the market) and from what I have seen in pretty good shape, also an international team (that is where I belong).

Let us, together, make our UFL even better for the greatest pleasure of our players.

I am your future colleague, I was born to code 3D and I do it since 25 years.

I could be available as soon as you need me. "Details" like the salary (though let us be decent) or the working hours (I am flexible, GMT+1 here) we can talk during the interview process.

I hope to hear from you and I wish you a wonderful day.

Kind Regards

Mik

WORK EXPERIENCES:

May 2011 – now (as a senior freelancer since 2017):

- Prototyping 3D Software developer at BMW (München)
- C and/or C++, simulation on Windows x86 and implementation on a Linux ARM system, QT
- OpenGL/OpenGL ES, GLSL
- Training new hires and providing formal presentations on 3D development
- Porting Futjitsu's 3D engine on Linux x86 with X11
- Benchmarking of new boards (Fujitsu ARM, Freescale, Tegra...)
- Creating detailed reports comparing 3D engines, functionality, assessing performance and usability (Unity, Unreal Engine, Ogre3D and many others)
- V structure or SCRUM
- Creation of a new multi-platform framework (Auto's signals, 3D Engine, Networking, Windowing's APIs and debugging functionalities in one Framework)
- Optimization of the Serie's software (Shaders, Code, Process)
- Augmented reality, developed high-class functionality with the new car projector, pedestrians/autos/path detection and "highlighting"
- Android Auto & Apple Carplay
- Eye tracking, Magic leap, Kinect, VR headset...
- INTEGRITY, extremely safe OS, programming has to be too, used in automotive or aircraft

August 2010 - November 2010:

- MAN Truck Assistance (München)
- Call center, truck assistance all over Europe in 3 languages (French, English, German)

July 2009 – March 2010:

- Junior LQA Lead Coordinator at Koch Media (München)
- Coordinating internal and external teams during test processes.
- Working on different projects at the same time on different platforms (PC, Xbox 360, PS3, Wii, DS, PSP)

March 2008 - July 2009:

- French Lead Tester at Koch Media (München)
- Testing video-games, checking any issues (language, performance or technical) or any Technical Requirements (console's guidelines). Reporting bugs using bug tracking tools, Mantis mainly.
- Working on multiple platforms (PC, Xbox 360, PS3, Wii, DS)

October 2002 - December 2005:

- Vice-president of the U.C.On LAN association
- Organized LAN long week-ends. It was open to visitors the afternoon, 500 people came.
- Contact the mayor to get a secure location. Contact different stores to be sponsored, borrowing some material and get some prizes to organize a tournament.
- Meetings reports, cutting kilometers of Ethernet cables...

June - July 2002:

- Secretary assistant of the Paris chess league
- In charge of organising the international chess championship 2002.

LANGUAGES:

- French: mother tongue.
- English: fluent both oral and written.
- German: fluent both oral and written.

INFORMATIC SKILLS:

- Developing languages: C, C++, GLSL, assembler (ARM on HP49g or DS), Java, Python, LUA
- 3D APIs: Direct3D, OpenGL, OpenGL ES, Vulkan
- Platforms: Windows, Linux (ARM or x86), Android, Xbox, DS (ARM), Raspberry Pi
- Software practiced: Visual Studio, GCC, QT, CMake, Unreal Engine, Unity, Word, Excel, Windows, Linux, PowerPoint, AutoCAD, 3DS Max, Photoshop, Lightwave, Blender, Gimp, GIT, Jira...
- Bug reporting software (Mantis, Bugtracker), console compliance (Nintendo's guideline, Xbox's TRCs, Sony's guideline)
- Expert gamer

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES:

- I love video games, poker, chess, board games, football, rugby, kayak, sailing
- Cooking for my friends
- Reading, Voltaire, Asimov, Victor Hugo, Astérix & Obélix
- Dungeon and Dragon, DMing or playing
- I did a bit of stand-up in a comedy club
- Handiwork, lego, DIY, Pi electronic, bike fixing, ikea's furniture, kitchen installation

EDUCATION AND TRAINING:

November 2012:

- RTOS (Real Time OS) Grundlagen & Intensiv-Workshop
- Formation, implementing an OS (from ground in C) with multi-threading functionality Threads, Semaphores, Interruptions, Processor's clock, etc

September 2005 - June 2007:

- Maîtrise (Master) in Informatics, université de Rennes.

September 2002 – June 2005:

 License (Bachelor) in Mathematics and Informatics, specialized in Informatics, université de Rennes.

June 2002:

- Baccalauréat S (A Level) specialized in Mathematics and Physics.

PERSONAL BACKGROUND:

I discovered video-games in the early 90's when my mom bought a second-hand MSX with a lot of games, I was instantly fascinated. Not only I liked to play video-games but I wanted to understand how is it done. When I was 10, Alone in the dark was a revelation. I will do that, I am going to be a 3D programmer. It became my hobby and since then I never stopped. I started to learn as an autodidact, first BASIC, then C, Pascal, C++ and even assembler for optimizations. I was doing some demomaking. I collected every source codes I could find, before Internet, you had to copy them from magazines. During high-school I was coding in assembler on my HP49g calculator. John Carmack was my idol. He still is and I keep on reading every new articles or source codes about video-games when they are published.

My studies path was clear, math, physic, computer science and more math. Perfect since I like it and I am good at it.

When I was 13 we had to designate 2 class representatives, I thought why not and got elected. Since then I got re-elected every years till the end of my studies. During the university I was also vice-president of a LAN association, a great success 100 of PCs and 500 visitors.

My Master thesis was about 3D Engines, once I was done it was time to find a job. I had an offer in Lyon and an offer in Munich, not speaking German I chose the adventurous path. I spent the first 2 years working for Koch Media, it was perfect for a first job, I discovered a new big city and I quickly made a lot of friends. After 2 years they had to give permanent contracts but the company was near bankruptcy, so they decided to outsource the all QA.

At that time I was starting to speak German, the easiest way to learn a language is love and I was not planing to leave my girl-friend. I had a quick experience in a call-center, it was not nice but now I have some funny stories about it. Meanwhile I kept on improving my German and I finally could apply for some Engineers jobs in German. Just when BMW decided their displays should switch from 2D to 3D, I got hired through a consultant company and worked on the prototype of their future electric cars. After 6 years and some personal events I decided to take a little break, I was insured to get back my job in 6 months. I went back to my hometown and my best friend, it was time to realize his dream. We bought a sailboat and crossed the Atlantic. It took 35 days and we are still best friends. We sold our boat in Florida before flying back to Europa. I came back to Munich, to my job, not anymore through a consultant company but as a freelancer.

MISC:

I'm a good and quick learner. Always willing to learn more.

I live in a shared flat since 15 years as the main renter, I met a lot of friends for life there and I learned a lot about how to resolve conflicts. My place was always the head-quarter, there is always a couch for a friend, a shoulder to cry on, a console and some board games for fun and some pasta-bolo for the hungry.

I implemented the Mario Kart Red Shell in the prototype car, through the HUD you can throw one and it will chase the car in front of you. It will stay a prototype since it would be too dangerous in serie.

I have the pretension to say I bring good mood in the office, a nice word here, a joke there, a blink, always willing to help. I think we work better in a nice ambiance.

REFERENCES:

Christian Moritz - Koch Media, Director Production - Europe

Michael Schmidt, Senior Manager - Koch Media, Localization, QA & Mastering

BMW, in German.

| Started | Name | Platform | Note | Published |
|---------|---------------------------------------|----------------|---|------------------------------|
| 03/08 | Warhammer Battle March | Xbox | First project, familiarizing with the tools and the platforms. | 09/08 |
| 04/08 | Foot 2 Rue | DS | First official project, platform game on DS. | 05/08 |
| 04/08 | Sacred 2 Angel collector | PC | Patch for Sacred 2 and some additional content for the collector edition. | 09/08 |
| 05/08 | STALKER : Clear Sky | PC | A game with a lot of content and a short deadline. We hired some external testers (Localsoft - Spain). First business trip, one month in Malaga leading the team there. | 09/08 |
| 06/08 | Tecktonik World Tour | DS | A dancing game just for the French market. | 11/08 |
| 07/08 | Gravity | PC Wii DS | A puzzle game developed for 3 platforms at the same time. | 11/08 |
| 09/08 | Secret Files 2 | PC | Point & click game, developed in 3 parts once every two months. | 05/09 |
| 09/08 | Mytran Wars | PSP | The project was mostly finished when the studio (Stormregion) bankrupt. We spend 2 weeks in Budapest to complete the project. A tough project since most of studio's employees left before the game was finished. | 11/08 USA 04/09 EUR |
| 10/08 | Jillian Michaels Fitness Ultimatum | Wii | A sport game using the Wii Balance Board. | 05/09 |
| 10/08 | Fritz Chess | PS3 | First project on PS3. | 05/09 |
| 11/08 | Line Rider | PC Wii DS | A multiplatform luge game. | 05/09 |
| 01/09 | 7Million | PC online | An online browser game | Beta |
| 01/09 | The Humans | PC DS | A prehistorical platform game. A survival horror game in the Tibetan | 05/09 |
| 01/09 | Cursed Mountain | Wii | mountains. | 08/09 |
| 03/09 | Sacred 2 Ice & Blood | PC | Add-on for Sacred 2. | 10/09 |
| 05/09 | Risen | PC Xbox | "Gothic 4". A huge RPG with a lot of content where I was coordinating the tests. | 10/09 |
| 05/09 | DJ Star | DS | A DJ game. | 09/09 |
| 06/09 | Pony Life | DS | A pony game. | 08/09 |
| 08/09 | Foot 2 Rue 2 | DS | Platform game on DS. | 11/09 |
| 09/09 | Prison Break - The Conspiracy | PC Xbox PS3 | License game, with the original cast from the show. | 03/10 |
| 08/09 | The Whispered World | PC | An oneiric point & click game | 04/10 |
| 11/09 | Horse Life 3 | DS | A horse simulation. | 04/10 |